How did you meet mom
你是怎么认识妈妈的？
I can tell you the date in september fourteenth , nineteen eighty four
我能告诉你具体的日期：一九八四年九月十四日。
Back when dinosaurs roamed the land
就是恐龙还在地球上游荡的年代。
Yeah
是的。
I was protecting her from the dinosaurs
我当时在保护她不被恐龙伤害。
And at least one day a week
而且几乎每周，
I left the rose scotch taped to her front door
我都会把一朵玫瑰花用胶带粘在她家门上。
And she didn't find that creepy
她不觉得这很怪吗？
Creepy
怪？
No , she actually found that nice
不，她其实觉得这很好。
I'd better tell your boyfriends about this
我最好把这个告诉你的男友们。
Well , a rose
嗯，一朵玫瑰，
You don't know who it's from
你还不知道是谁送的。
Oh no , she knew it was who is from
哦不，她知道是谁送的。
Okay
好吧。
Now what made you decide you want to adopt a child
那是什么让你们决定要领养一个孩子？
Mommy had an ectopic pregnancy
妈妈曾经有过宫外孕，
Which means the pregnancy was in the tubes
也就是胚胎长在输卵管里。
After that she couldn't get pregnant
之后她就不能再自然怀孕了。
We considered adopting and we actually said we wanted a smart assertikid
我们考虑了领养，而且我们说希望找一个聪明、有主见的孩子。
Yeah , you don't take this the wrong way
对，你别往坏处想，
But we interviewed intelligence over beauty
但我们把智商排在了外貌前面。
Great
好吧。
Well , but no , i mean he turned out to be both
不不，我的意思是，他后来两样都有。
But that's what we said
但这就是我们当初说的。
And when we got to talk to the nannies about you
后来我们和保育员聊起你，
They said you were very determined
她们说你意志非常坚定，
Little child huang see , very strong
小黄，非常厉害。
Well that's right
没错，就是这样。
Ha ha ha
哈哈哈。
I want to tell you something
我想告诉你一件事，
You have absolutely changed my life
你彻底改变了我的人生。
The most interesting thing for me was the idea of the red thread
对我来说，最有意义的是"红线"这个概念。
In chinese adoptions and in the chinese culture
在中国的领养文化里，
The red thread means that we are with our souls connected to a specific person
红线象征着我们的灵魂与某个特定的人紧紧相连。
and we got you
而那个人就是你。
and i am so pleased that you're part of my life
我非常庆幸你成了我生命的一部分。
I'm not crying
我没有哭。
You're crying
是你在哭。
My name is amy and this is my dad
我叫艾米，这是我的爸爸。
We're following up fifteen years from the last time that we recorded
这是距离我们上次录音十五年后的续集。
Since then i've lived so many phases of life
这些年来，我经历了人生的许多阶段。
I have gotten my braces off
我把牙套摘了，
Thank god i've gone through college and i learned to swear like a sailor
感谢老天，我上了大学，还学会了说粗口。
Rt you know , i've just gotten older
总之，我只是变老了。
You was such a good kid
你以前是个很好的孩子，
You know , you you never dated a biker
你从来没跟什么骑摩托车的人约会过。
Ha ha ! you know
哈哈！你知道吗，
You know i still could
我现在还有机会呢。
You still could
你还有机会。
I could become the biker
我也可以自己去骑。
U you came with a spark that we could nurture
你来到我们身边时，带着一种我们可以去呵护的火花，
But we couldn't create
但那是我们无法创造的。
Well you taught me that it was okay to push back
你教会了我，顶回去也是可以的，
And really gave me an opportunity to be strong
你真的给了我一个变得坚强的机会。
So many people say they're self made
很多人说自己是白手起家，
But i probably would not have gotten here without you guys
但我很可能没有你们就走不到今天。
What can i say
我能说什么呢，
I just love you so much honey
我就是那么爱你，宝贝。
I love you too
我也爱你。